《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously on "Arrow"...
他不能知道你是他父亲
He can't know that you're his father,
别人也不能知道
and nobody else can.
萨曼莎  我已经心有所属了
Samantha, there is someone in my life now.
请别逼我隐瞒她好吗
Please don't make me keep this from her.
你想见儿子的话  就必须这么做
You will if you want a relationship with my son.
我知道奥利弗·奎恩最在乎谁
I know who Oliver Queen cares about more than anyone.
诺拉  宝贝  我想给你介绍个人
Nora, honey, there's someone I'd like you to meet.
这是威廉
This is William.
这是可植入生物刺激素
It's an implantable biostimulant.
这个小玩意儿能让我再次走路
This little piece of technology's gonna help me walk again?
在将它植入你的脊椎之后  没错
After it's implanted in your spine, yes.
我可以的
I can do this.
我可以的  我绝对可以的
I can do this. I can so totally do this.
对  你可以  但不论如何
Yes, you can, but either way,
我们都在
we've got you.
别有压力  斯莫克小姐
It's no pressure here, Miss Smoak.
柯蒂斯的植入技术本来就希望渺茫
Curtis' implant is the longest of long shots.
我还以为你会多一些信心呢
I was expecting a little more encouragement
你可是发明这玩意儿的天才的丈夫
from the husband of the genius who invented the thing.
我的爱人能创造技术奇迹
My man works miracles with technology,
但人体的原理却大不相同
but the human body doesn't play by the same rules.
开始吧
Well, here we go.
Here we go.
来吧  开始吧
Here we go, here we go.
■
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
可以走了
Yeah. We're going.
翻译  Z小花儿  Silence  Reginamoon
没事的  扶住你了  扶住你了
Ok. It's ok. Got you, got you, got you.
翻译   天青月白 小暴徒  补课狂魔 木浅薰
好吧  一步都没走出去
Well, that went nowhere.
校对   苹果果  Z小花儿  沫沫
精校   陈小圈
柯蒂斯说过我们是怎么相遇的吗
Curtis ever tell you how we met?
他当时过来治疗跟腱炎
He came in with Achilles Tendonitis.
时间轴风吹来的那片云
他当时在为奥运会资格赛训练
He was training to qualify for the Olympics,
所以他当时只在乎结果
so all he cared about was results.
特效&后期   咖啡Lee[绿箭侠]       总监   苹果果
我花了几周时间才让他
Took me weeks just to get him
把注意力放在真正重要的事上
focused on what really mattered.
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
是他的理疗师有多帅吗
How handsome his therapist was?
是康复  得对自己有耐心
Healing. Got to be patient with yourself.
这需要时间
These things take time.
你确定康克林说的是真的吗
Are you sure what Conklin told you was the truth?
康克林当时快死了
Conklin was dying.
他没理由撒谎
He had no reason to lie.
不管瑞特有什么计划
Whatever Reiter has planned,
他会杀了这里所有人
he's gonna kill everyone here.
奎恩先生...
Mr. Queen...
看来我们的成功近在咫尺
it appears we are within striking distance of my prize.
到时希望你们俩能和我一同见证
I want you both at my side when I claim it.
我才不在乎你那迷信的变革运动
I don't give a damn about your superstitious crusade!
不管怎样  你们都将见证它的完成
Nevertheless, you'll both bear witness to its fruition.
-你还好吗  -我吗
- You ok? - Me?
我知道你会这么问我
I knew you were gonna ask me,
所以我想还是抢先一步
so I thought I'd beat you to the punch.
你还好吗
Are you ok?
一个聪明绝顶的人
A guy, a brilliant guy
说他可以在我的脊椎里放个微芯片
says he can put a microchip in my spine
我就又能走路了
and I will walk again.
作为专业极客  我还是分得清科幻和现实的
I'm enough of a geek to know science fiction when I see it.
你还是很失望
You're still disappointed?
是啊  你知道...
Yeah. You know...
这很傻
it's stupid.
跟我说说
Talk to me.
我希望能在婚礼那天走过红毯
I wanted to be able to walk down the aisle on our wedding day.
我这铁石心肠都被你们感动了
Aw, you two just melt my stone-cold heart.
你们让我差点又相信爱情了
You almost make me believe in love again.
很高兴见到你  奎恩先生
Nice to see you, Mr. Queen.
圣诞节过得还好吗
How was your Christmas?
你个混...
Son of a bi--
你真是位英勇的政治候选人
Ooh! Oh. You're so brave for a political candidate
和改革党人
and reformed party boy.
对了  豪车的事真抱歉  这轮椅挺不错
Oh. Sorry about the limo, love the wheelchair.
我建议做成机动的
Might I suggest motorized.
我们有力量超强的朋友
We have extremely powerful friends.
你不知道你是在跟谁作对
You do not know who you're messing with.
如果能让你开心
If it makes you happy,
我们的作对今天就了结
the messing ends today.
我试过招你入伙  奎恩先生
I tried to bring you into the fold, Mr. Queen,
我试过绑架你的至亲至爱
I tried to kidnap your nearest and dearest,
我试过杀死你  但都没成功
I tried to kill you, but none of that took.
正如她说的  你根本不知道是在和谁作对
Well, like she said, you don't know who you're messing with.
我想那是真的
I suspect that is true,
但俗话说  或许应该说
but as they say-- well, or should--
第四次一定交好运
the fourth time is the charm.
没关系  看看吧
Go ahead. Take a look.
我可以等
I'll wait.
威廉把我当成他母亲的朋友了
William thinks that I'm friends with his mother.
真好笑
Funny.
对了
Anywho,
周五六点  你得召开新闻发布会
6:00 on Friday, you're gonna hold a press conference
宣布自己退出市长竞选
and drop out of the mayoral race.
对了  是晚上六点
Oh, that's 6 P.M., by the way.
我会在家用新买的电视
I will be at home watching you
收看你的发布会
from my brand-new television.
他让你在手机上看什么
What did he show you on your phone?
威廉是谁
Who's William?
他是我儿子
He's my son.
绿 箭
第四季  第十五集
求你说句话
Please say something.
费莉西蒂  听我解释
Felicity, I can explain.
闭嘴
Stop.
我不想再听到谎话
I cannot hear another lie.
你知道  这不是那么简单
You know, it's--it's more complicated than that.
老天  奥利弗  世界上只有你
God, Oliver. Are you the only person
认为真相很复杂吧
on this planet that considers the truth complicated?
跟你明说吧  我不在乎
Just to be clear, I don't care
你有一个孩子
that you have a child.
我无法相信的是  你有一个孩子
I can't believe that you have a child
却没告诉我
that you didn't tell me about.
如果你的第一本能永远都是隐瞒真相
What does it say about our relationship
那我们的关系还算什么
if your first instinct is to always hide the truth?
威廉的母亲明确提出
William's mother made a condition
如果我想见到他
that the only way I would be allowed
就必须答应不向任何人透露他的存在
to meet my son is if I agreed to keep him secret,
连你也不能
even from you.
谁会发这种最后通牒
Who even makes that kind of ultimatum?
只是一个母亲想要保护她的儿子
Just a-a mother who's trying to protect her son,
她认为让我远离他的世界
and she thought that the best thing for him
对他才是最好的
was to keep his world separate from mine.
发生了这么多事之后
After everything that has happened,
你能说她这样做是错的吗
can you really say that she was wrong?
但这样做没用  不是吗
Well, it didn't work, did it?
达克还是发现了
Somehow, Darhk still found out.
我们收到了紧急呼叫
Hey. We got your 911.
达克来过
Darhk paid us a visit.
他抓走了一个十岁小男孩做人质
He's holding a 10-year-old boy hostage,
说如果奥利弗
says that he will release him
放弃竞选市长  他就会释放他
if Oliver drops out of the mayoral race.
我们去联系艾利克斯
Let's get in touch with Alex,
让他安排周五晚上六点召开记者招待会
have him schedule a press conference for Friday at 6 P.M.
你不是真要这么做吧
You're not actually going for this, are you?
达克抓走的小男孩  威廉
The boy Darhk has-- William--
是我儿子
he's my son.
我也是刚刚才知道
Yeah. I just found out, too.
显然  知道威廉存在的人
Apparently, the only two people that knew
只有奥利弗和达克
about William were Oliver and Darhk.
其实我也知道了
Actually, I found out, too.
我们下一步要怎么做
Um, what's our next plan?
威廉住在中城  对吧
William lives in Central City, right?
对
Yep.
我会打给巴里  看中城警局有没有办法
I will call Barry, see what CCPD can do.
我可以告诉巴里  威廉是你的...
Is it ok if I tell Barry that William's your--
巴里也知道
Barry knows, too.
也联系一下马尔科姆
Let's also get in touch with Malcolm.
刺客联盟那件事之后  他另有打算
He has an ax to grind after what happened with the League,
而且马尔科姆也知道这件事
and, um, Malcolm knows, as well.
也许算算多少人不知道你有儿子
Maybe it would be easier to list the people
这样会简单点
who don't know about your son.
萨曼莎来了
Ahem. Samantha's here.
萨曼莎是谁
Who's Samantha?
她是威廉的妈妈
It's William's mother.
奎恩
市长
艾利克斯
Alex.
她说她叫萨曼莎·克莱顿
She said her name was Samantha Clayton.
一张百万美元的支票上
The name struck a bell
有她的名字  你跟西娅说过
from the million-dollar check you told Thea
不会有问题的
wasn't gonna be a problem.
的确不会有问题
It's not gonna be a problem.
好吧  那我为什么刚刚收到
OK. Then why did I just get a 911 text
西娅发的紧急短信说你要退出竞选
from Thea telling me that you're pulling out of the race?
你有威廉的消息吗
Have you heard from William?
知道他的下落吗
Do you know where he is?
不知道  但是我会尽全力去找
I don't, but I'm doing everything I can.
我就知道
Oh! I knew it.
发现他不见的那一刻起  我就知道
I knew the second I realized he was gone,
我就知道你和这肯定脱不了干系
I knew that you had to have some sort of involvement in this.
天呐  我当时怎么想的
Oh, my God. What was I thinking
让你知道他的存在
letting you get into his life?
两个月后  他就失踪了
Two months later, and he's missing.
萨曼莎  我要你告诉我当时的经过
Samantha, I need you to tell me exactly what happened.
不  奥利弗  告诉我到底是怎么回事
No, Oliver. You need to tell me what the hell is going on,
而且你要立刻把我儿子还给我
and you need to give me my son back right now!
我正在努力  但请你告诉我事情的经过
I am trying, but you need to tell me what happened, please.
我上楼去叫他吃饭  他就不见了
I-- I went upstairs to get him for dinner, and he was gone.
不见了
Gone.
没留下纸条  没有挣扎的痕迹
No-- no note, no sign of struggle.
就这样消失了
Just vanished.
我打电话给中城警局  他们到处找过了
I called the CCPD, and they have been looking everywhere,
但是已经四十八小时了
but it's already been 48 hours,
还是没找到
and still nothing,
然后一名犯罪现场分析人员把我拉到一旁
but then a crime scene technician pulled me aside
说我得告诉你这件事
and said that I needed to talk to you about this.
是巴里·艾伦吗
Barry Allen?
没错  就是他
Yes. That's the one.
奥利弗  你保证过的
Oliver, you promised.
-我  -你向我保证过的
- I-- - You promised me
你不会向任何人提起我儿子
that you wouldn't tell anyone about my son.
巴里是猜到的  这不重要了
Barry figured it-- that's not what's important right now.
重要的是我会尽全力
What is important is I'm gonna do everything--
我是说动用我的全部力量
and I mean absolutely everything in my power--
我们会把他找回来的
and we will get him back!
你能做什么  奥利弗
What can-- what can you do, Oliver?
整个警局都束手无策
What can you do that the entire police force
你还能做什么
hasn't been able to do?
萨曼莎
S-Samantha...
我就是绿箭侠
I'm the Green Arrow.
太荒谬了
This doesn't make any sense.
我说过
Well, like I said,
我和从前不一样了
I'm not the person that I used to be.
萨曼莎  这些都是我的朋友
Samantha, these are my friends.
他们会帮我们找到威廉的
They're gonna help us find William.
你可能还记得
You probably remember...
劳蕾尔·兰斯
Laurel Lance.
非常抱歉你的儿子不见了  萨曼莎
I am so sorry that you're going through this, Samantha.
我们会帮你找回威廉的
We will help you get William back.
劳蕾尔
Look, Laurel.
只有一次
It was one time,
当时我知道你和奥利弗在一起
and I knew that you and Oliver were together,
但我年纪小  又蠢又自私
but I was young and stupid and selfish,
我应该跟你说实话的
and I should have been honest with you.
不  这是奥利弗的责任
No. Oliver should have been.
别多想了
Come on.
中城警局有什么发现吗
Does CCPD have anything?
没  没留下任何线索
No. It was a clean grab.
有没有什么其他的方向可查
Do we have any other angles we can work,
除了马尔科姆之外
other than Malcolm?
要找到威廉不是问题
Finding William isn't the problem.
击败达米恩·达克才是关键
Beating Damien Darhk is.
每次我们面对他
Every time we've faced him,
我们都输得彻底
we have been beaten thoroughly.
那是因为我们没办法抵抗他的魔力
That's because we can't go against his magic.
我们只需要更努力地抗争
We just need to fight harder,
更聪明地抗争
we need to fight smarter.
你知道吗  奥利弗
You know, Oliver,
所谓疯狂就是指重复地做同一件事
insanity is doing the same thing over and over again
却期待不同的结果
and expecting a different result.
我们需要一个新的策略
We need a new strategy.
康斯坦丁能帮上忙吗
What bout Constantine?
他下地狱了
He's in hell.
真的吗  怎么回事
Really? What's going on?
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
他是真真正正身处地狱之中
I mean, he's actually literally in hell.
但我还认识一个人
But I might know someone else.
她的名字叫玛丽·麦凯布
Her name is Mari Mccabe.
她拥有一个有魔力的图腾
She possesses a totem which is powered by magic.
她自称为雌狐
She calls herself Vixen.
底特律
那东西是什么鬼
What the hell was that thing?
克里格付的钱可不够我们弄清楚
Cerico doesn't pay us enough to find out!
滚出来  有点男子汉的样子
Come on out. Face us like a man!
我有个更好的主意
I've got a better idea.
不如我像个女人一样揍你一顿如何
How about I kick your ass like a woman instead?
我能搞定的
I had that under control.
-我知道  -怎么
- I know. - What?
星城还不够你忙的吗
Not enough in Star City to keep you busy?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我也得整一个这样的基地
I have got to get me one of these.
-玛丽  -你好  劳蕾尔
- Mari. - Laurel, hey.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
我也是
You, too.
玛丽  这位是约翰·狄格尔
Mari, this is John Diggle
这是我妹妹西娅
and my sister Thea.
很荣幸
Pleasure.
很高兴见到你
It's nice to meet you.
很抱歉在这么糟糕的情况下见面
Sorry it's under such horrible circumstances.
你和费利西蒂通过电话了
You spoke to Felicity on the phone.
这位是萨曼莎  威廉的母亲
And this is Samantha, William's mother.
她是我的朋友
She's a friend,
一个被称为雌狐的底特律英雄
a hero in Detroit they call Vixen.
去年玛丽和我有过一次很刺激的交手
Mari and I had an animated encounter last year,
从此之后我们便一直保持联系
and we've stayed in touch ever since.
你怎么能帮我找到我儿子
How are you gonna help me find my son?
用魔力
With magic.
魔力
Magic.
没错  这说来话长了
Yeah. It's a long story,
但简单说来就是
but the short version is that
这个图腾让我
this totem gives me the ability to channel
能与所有动物的灵魂沟通
the ashe-- or the spirit-- of any animal.
你身上有威廉的东西吗
Do you have anything of William's with you?
有  只有这个
Yes, I do. Just this.
这是他最喜欢的
It's his favorite.
你敢把这事告诉巴里
Don't you dare tell Barry about this.
他在市里  我觉得我能找到他
He's in the city. I think I can find him.
很好  狄格和我会掩护你
Ok. Good. Dig and I will cover you.
劳蕾尔  联系你父亲
Laurel, get in touch with your father.
我们得通知星城警局
We're gonna loop in the SCPD.
费利西蒂  我需要你...
Felicity, I need you to...
你愿意和萨曼莎待在这里吗
Would it be all right if you sat with Samantha?
帮忙搜索资料是吧  没问题
Working up a search profile. Sure.
谢谢你  西娅
Thank you. Thea.
好的  马尔科姆在过来的路上了
Yeah. Malcolm's coming over.
我去和他谈
I'll go talk to him.
我们会找到他  他会没事的
We're gonna find him. He's gonna be ok.
好的
Okay.
你感觉到了吗
Can you feel it?
这股能量  如此原始
The energy, primordial.
那是什么
What is that?
是命运  奎恩先生
Destiny, Mr. Queen.
命运
不
我们是更宏伟的存在
我知道你在这里
I know you're here.
没必要像怪物一样躲在阴影里
There's no need to lurk in the shadows like the bogeyman.
你有一段时间没见到我了
You haven't seen me in a while.
我已经不是原来的我了
And I'm not the man I used to be.
是啊  我知道
Yeah, I know.
他们和我说了
They told me.
不太好看  是吧
Not pretty, is it?
本来有可能更糟的
Well, could have been a lot worse.
你的头都有可能被砍掉
Could have chopped your head off.
那样的话还更好一些
And I would have been better off for it.
他把联盟从我手中抢走
He took the League away from me
给了娜莎·厄尔·高福
and gave it to Nyssa Al Ghul.
那难道比救你女儿一命更重要吗
And that was more important than saving your daughter's life?
没错  那部分我也听说了
Yeah. Heard about that part of the story, too.
拒绝和娜莎谈判来救我一命
Refusing to bargain with Nyssa to save me.
我本意是想救你一命
My intention was to save your life
同时保住我的权位
and to keep my seat of power
以便构建一个更好的世界
for the betterment of the world.
你把奥利儿子的事告诉达克了吗
Did you tell Darhk about Ollie's son?
你真觉得我会做这样的事吗
Do you really think I'd do something like that?
回答我
Just answer the question.
没有
No.
没有  我不回答
No, I won't
因为你应该更了解我
because you should know me better
而不至于问出这种问题
than to ask me the question.
我是太了解你了
I know you all too well.
你应该知道一件事  西娅
You should know one thing, Thea.
无论发生什么  我都会永远爱你
No matter what happens, I will always love you.
为父者皆如此
It's what fathers do.
这真是个疯狂的世界啊
Crazy world we live in, huh?
超能力者  魔力
Metahumans, magic,
奥利弗·奎恩当了父亲
Oliver Queen father.
很抱歉我没告诉你
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
不用  老兄  我完全理解
No, man. I totally get it.
萨曼莎让你很为难
Samantha put you in a tough spot.
对你而言这个决定一定很不容易
Couldn't have been an easy decision for you.
我完全理解你为何做此决定
I totally get why you made it.
她是对的
She was right.
我不知道威廉的存在  他要安全得多
William was safer when I didn't know about him,
如果我一直没有发现
so maybe if I never find out, I--
不要那样想  伙计
Can't even go there, man.
你会被自己折磨疯的
You'll eat yourself up inside
不停地想"如果这样"或者"也许那样"
with the "What if this" or the "Maybe that."
这就是做父母要经历的
Part of being a parent.
现在最重要的是
Most important thing now is focusing
把你儿子安全救回来
on getting your boy back home safe.
约翰
John...
你是怎么做到的
How do you do it?
我知道每晚莎拉在哪  奥利弗
I know where Sara is every night, Oliver.
我知道她在做什么  和谁在一起
I know what she's doing, who she's with.
她每天都能
She sees my face
见到我
every single day.
我在她身边
I'm there for her,
并且她和我都知道
and she knows, and I know
我绝不会让她发生任何事
that I would never let anything bad happen to her.
她就在我身边  兄弟
I keep her close, man,
你这样才能保护儿子的安全
and that's how you keep your children safe.
他穿着一件蓝色帽衫  格子衬衣
Ok. He was wearing a blue hoodie, plaid shirt,
灰色卫裤  头戴一顶镶钻的棒球帽
gray corduroys, and, um, a diamonds baseball cap.
他是个棒球迷
He's a big fan.
奥利弗也喜欢棒球
Oliver likes baseball, too.
我竟然还希望父子两个不要太相似
Here's hoping that the innate fatherly influence stops there.
他身上有相貌什么特征吗
Um, does he have any distinguishing features,
比如雀斑  胎记之类的
freckles, birthmarks, anything like that?
奥利弗告诉我他有个深爱的人
Oliver told me that there was someone in his life,
特别的人  她叫费利西蒂
someone special, and her name was Felicity.
他想要告诉你
He wanted to tell you,
但是我不允许
and I wouldn't let him.
我不知道他现在变成什么样了
I didn't know who he was now,
也不知道他现在是个什么样的人
I didn't know what kind of person he was.
大家都这样
That's going around.
拜托请记住是我让他在你
Just try and remember that I was the one that made him choose
和了解他儿子之间做了选择
between you and knowing his son.
好了  我已经让整个队伍
All right. I got the whole force,
反正剩下的都用上了
what's left of them anyway,
去搜寻威廉了
canvassing for William.
谢谢
Thank you.
你看起来没有我想象中的惊讶
You don't seem as surprised as I expected.
花花公子奥利弗·奎恩搞大女生的肚子吗
What, that party boy Oliver Queen knocked up some girl?
我很惊讶竟然没有出现一堆
I'm amazed there isn't an army of little Olivers
小奥利弗跑来跑去
running around out there.
好吧  可能还有
Well, there may be.
他那时候绝对是社交广阔
Certainly got around back then.
是的
Yeah.
你还好吗
Ahh. You ok?
我不知道
I don't know.
孩子的母亲萨曼莎
It's the mother Samantha.
他们在一起的时候我们两个还在谈恋爱
She was with him when--when I was with him.
宝贝
Oh, baby.
我不知道为什么还会心痛
I don't know why it still stings.
都过去很久了
It was a million years ago,
而且我也知道奥利弗背叛了我
and it's not like I didn't know that Oliver cheated on me.
没错  这是一回事
Yeah, but that's one thing.
但知道他有个孩子
Knowing he had a kid?
很遗憾  宝贝
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
过来
Come here.
谢谢
Thank you.
是奥利弗
It's Oliver.
他知道威廉被关押的地方了
He knows where William's being held.
我看到有四个警卫在屋顶巡逻
I count 4 guards patrolling the roof.
玛丽已经就位
Mari's in position.
我还在想需要多久
I wondered how long it would take
你的好兄弟奥利弗才会把你找来
for your buddy Oliver to drag you into this.
男孩在哪里
Where's the boy?
他很好  就在你们今晚跑来
Oh, he's fine. I had him moved about
打扰我两分钟之前  我已经把他送走了
two minutes before you and your posse disturbed my evening in.
知道吗  你也许该学着
You know what? You might want to learn
更加小心谨慎点
to be a little bit more discreet.
你考虑过穿黑色而不是绿色吗
Have you considered black instead of green?
告诉我  你把他带到哪里去了
You tell me where you've taken him.
不然呢  你要朝我射箭吗
Or what? You'll fire an arrow at me?
我想我们都知道结果会如何
I think we've seen that movie before.
我赢了  你输了  重来结果也一样
I win, you lose, rinse, repeat.
这一次结果会不同
This time, it's different.
真的吗
Oh, really?
男孩在哪
Where's the boy?
你有一些很有趣的朋友
You have some very interesting friends.
天啊  我已经很久没有见过这种佩饰了
My, my. I haven't seen that trinket in a dog's age.
是米昌佳省  我说的对吗
The M'Changa Province, am I right?
别动
Stay.
我喜欢你
Oh, I like you,
我喜欢的人可不多
and I don't like many people.
我抓住你了
I got you!
发生了什么
What happened?
他去哪里了
Where did he go?
我追踪不到他
I can't track him.
达克受魔力的保护
Darhk's protected by magic.
不  不只是达克  也追踪不到威廉了
No, not just Darhk. I lost William.
威廉在哪里  发生了什么
Where's William? What happened?
有点小挫折  但我们不会放弃的
We had a small setback, but we are not giving up.
挫折  什么意思
Setback? What do you mean?
匿名电话
Hey. Blocked I.D.
你好
Hello?
奥利弗  你今晚过得如何
Oh. Hi, Oliver. How is your evening going?
我今晚可过得丰富多彩
Mine somewhat eventful.
刚才你的几个朋友突然
Some of your friends stopped by my place earlier
来拜访我  非常没有礼貌
completely unannounced. Very rude.
我想和我儿子说话  达克
I want to talk to my son, Darhk.
我想知道他是否安全
I want to know that he's safe.
这肯定是你儿子第一次被绑架
Oh, this must be the first time your son's been kidnapped
因为你很显然不知道这是怎么回事
because clearly you don't understand how these things work.
我才能提要求
I make the demands.
好吧  你提了  我已经同意了
Well, you've made them, and I've agreed.
周五晚上我会退出竞选
Friday night, I'm dropping out of the race.
那还等什么
Why wait?
为了减少你绿衣服朋友搞破坏的时间
Give your green friend less time to botch things up.
你去找一台电视摄像机
So go find yourself a television camera.
我想知道我儿子是否安全
I want to know that my son is safe!
另外  我要你全力支持鲁维·亚当斯
And by the way, you're going to completely endorse Ruvé Adams,
这样就省得再计算烦人的选票了
save us all the trouble of those pesky little write-in ballots.
他把时间提前了
He moved up the timetable.
想让我今晚就放弃竞选
Wants me to drop out of the race tonight.
西娅  把这消息告诉艾利克斯
Thea, let Alex know.
真是抱歉
I am so sorry.
我知道你找我来是要用魔力对抗魔力  可是...
I know you brought me here to fight magic with magic, but--
玛丽  这不怪你
Mari, this is not on you.
对于达克的能力我们几乎一无所知
There is still so much that we don't know about Darhk's power.
我们...我们甚至不知道他力量的来源
We--we don't-- we don't even know what the source of it is.
等等  我从这项链中获取力量
Wait. I get my powers from this necklace.
没有了它  我只是一个努力成为时尚设计师的人
Without it, I'm just a wannabe fashion designer
与自己的养父同住在一个屋檐下
who lives at home with her foster dad.
迄今为止  所有我遇到过拥有神秘力量的人
So up to now, everyone I've gone up against with mystical powers
都有类似我这种的图腾
has had some sort of totem like mine.
会不会达克也有样东西能给他魔力
What if Darhk has an object that helps him with his magic?
我觉得有
I think he does.
有那么一两次我撞见他站在橱柜前
I walked in on him once or twice in front of this cabinet thing,
柜子里面  是个类似于神像的东西
and inside, there's some kind of, I don't know, idol.
你能画出来吗
Can you draw it for me?
可以  我试试
Yeah. I'll give it a whirl.
奥利弗  调查神像这条路
Ok, Oliver. What if this little art project
-如果是个死胡同怎么办  -那...
- doesn't yield any results? - Well--
如果耗时过多呢
And what if it takes too long?
玛丽和兰斯队长
M-mari and Captain Lance
寻求的是终结达克的方法
are working on a way to eventually stop Darhk.
眼下  我必须要救出威廉
Right now, I have to save William.
陌生人禁入
他说的话什么意思
What's he saying?
不管是什么  肯定不是好事
Whatever it is, it's not good.
你们会因亵渎而付出死亡的代价
我们得马上离开这里
We have to get out of here now!
瑞特  你干什么
Reiter, what are you doing?
向我证明我没看错你
Proving what I know about you is true.
别把我们和这东西留在这
You can't leave us in here with it.
瑞特
Reiter!
你
You.
你有进去的资格
You are worthy to pass.
晚上好  感谢大家在如此短时间内赶来
Good evening, thank you for coming on such short notice.
我之所以参加此次竞选  是因为
When I entered this race, it was because
当时没有人愿意在公众面前挺身而出
no one else was willing to step into the spotlight.
我一直都希望自己的行为
It has always been my hope that my actions
可以激励他人
would inspire others.
4个月后  希望变成了现实
4 months later, and they have.
鉴于此  以下内容即刻生效
Knowing that, effective immediately,
我将停止竞选活动
I will be suspending my campaign
并将鼎力支持鲁维·亚当斯
and throwing my full support behind Ruvé Adams.
特别要对
Now I would like to take a moment
所有支持我的人表示感谢
to thank all of my supporters
感谢你们的努力
for all of your hard work.
你们所做的努力将被永远铭记
What you've done will not be forgotten.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
新的统计数据出炉了
New numbers are out.
你以16个点领先
You're leading by 16 points.
对不起  艾利克斯
Alex, I'm sorry.
我知道你全心全意投入到这次竞选中
I know that you put your heart and soul into this campaign, and--
你的演说生涯已经结束了
and your days of speech-making are now behind you.
听着  我要的不是歉意
Look, man. I don't want sorry.
我就需要一个解释而已
I just want an explanation.
不能给你解释才是歉意所在
That's why I'm sorry.
不能说出真相的感觉很糟吧
Sucks when you can't tell the truth.
萨曼莎告诉我最后通牒的事了
Samantha told me about her ultimatum.
我只是觉得她最终会信任我的
I just figured that eventually she'd trust me.
是啊  你施展魅力就行
Yeah. You'd work your Oliver Queen charm.
如果没有你
I didn't want to be a part of William's life
我不愿成为威廉生命中的一部分
without the opportunity for you to be a part of his life.
约翰说得很明白
John's made it pretty clear that, uh,
我本该更努力地
I should have made more of an effort
成为威廉生命的一部分
to be a part of William's life
并且保证他安全最好的办法
and that the best way to keep him safe
就是让他待在自己身边
would have been to keep him close,
即便要面对这些危险
Even with all of this.
新闻全都是你辞选的消息
Your resignation's all over the news.
有达克的消息吗
Have you heard from Darhk?
还没
Not yet.
还真是说曹操  曹操到
Speak of the devil literally.
不是达克  是玛丽
It's not Darhk. It's Mari.
她有所发现
She has something.
我把兰斯队长所画的达克的神像
I e-mailed Captain Lance's drawing Of Darhk's idol
发给了我在底特律大学的朋友
to a friend of mine at Detroit University.
那他知道这是什么吗
And did he recognize it?
那是个虔诚神像
It's a khushu idol,
十分罕见  力量十分强大
very rare, very powerful,
但要保持跟地球上众多魔力小径之一
but its power requires a constant connection
保持连接不断才能获取力量
to one of the earth's ley lines.
从未想到我会说出这话  什么意思
I never thought I'd say this, but huh?
这样  把魔力想象成无线网络
Ok. Think wi-fi for magic,
神像就是他的网络连接
and the idol is his Internet connection.
如果麦卡勒斯特教授的观点没错
If professor Macalester's theory is correct
这张地图也很精确
and this map is accurate--
那么达克肯定就藏在这几条魔力小径附近
Then Darhk must be holed up near one of these ley lines
以便于他接收到最强的信号
in order for him to get the strongest signal.
我会把我们曾遭遇达克的所有位置信息
I'll start cross-referencing all the locations
进行相互比对
that we've encountered Darhk.
你已经退出竞选了
And you pulled out of the race.
为什么这家伙还不把我儿子还给我
Why isn't this man giving me my son back?
他会的  一切都会好起来的
He will, and everything will be fine.
你总是这么说  可并没有什么转机
You keep saying that, but it hasn't been yet.
你已经尽自己最大努力了
You're doing everything you possibly can.
别自责
You can't beat yourself up about it.
你也不是很了解我  不是吗
Well, you don't know me very well, do you?
就在圣诞节前
Just before Christmas,
达克抓走了西娅  费利西蒂  约翰
Darhk took Thea, Felicity, John,
把他们关了起来
held them captive.
我们达成协议用我来换取他们自由
We agreed that I would trade myself for them.
我依约前去
I did,
但达克却没履行诺言
and darhk did not live up to his end of the bargain.
所以你担心会再一次被耍
So you're worried that's playing itself out again now.
我们会救回威廉的  奥利弗
We're gonna get William back, Oliver.
但救出来后
But when we do,
我觉得你应该考虑一下
I think you should consider that...
也许放手并不是一件坏事
maybe letting him go isn't such a bad thing.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我听到了你跟费利西蒂说要把他留在身边
Well, I heard what you told Felicity about keeping him close.
我有猫头鹰一样灵敏的耳朵
Owl ears.
我一直没见过我的亲生父母
I never knew my real parents.
我在寄宿家庭长大
I grew up in foster home,
这一生中我都一直在想
and my whole life, I wondered,
我是谁  我从哪来
"Who am I? Where did I come from?
我的亲生父母为什么不要我
Why didn't my real parents want me?"
一个男孩应该知道自己的父亲是谁
A boy should know who his father is.
他是应该知道  他也会知道的
He should, and he will.
但是得知现在威廉的处境
But knowing what William's going through right now,
我明白了我还没准备好知道答案是什么
I realize that I wasn't ready for the answers.
了解我的血统  我的力量
Learning about my heritage, my powers,
了解我母亲为了保护我而逃避的恶魔
the evil my mother fled our homeland to protect me from,
不应该由孩子去承担这样的重担
no child should have to carry that burden.
我是说  看看你的周围
I mean, look around you.
奥利弗  你能给他最好的礼物就是童年
Oliver, the best gift you can give him is his childhood.
让他尽可能久地远离你
Keep him as far away from your world for as long as possible.
我无法想象还能有更大的牺牲了
I can't imagine a greater sacrifice.
但是做父母不就是这样吗
Isn't that what parenthood is?
伙计们
Hey, guys.
我们好像发现了点什么
I think we found something.
达克经常移动他的神像  这很合理  但是...
Darhk moves his idol around, which makes sense, but--
这样一来想找到他要难得多
It makes him a whole lot harder to track.
没错  不过在参考了
Right, but after referencing
大量的卫星信号  热成像数据
a buttload of satellite feeds, thermal imaging data,
还有地脉图之后  我觉得达克就在
and the ley line map, I think Darhk is located
天空之森一处居住区外
out on a compound in Sky Woods.
你好
Hello?
演讲很精彩  你在电视上看起来真帅
Very good speech. You look great on television.
三小时之内到尼尔森广场
Nelson plaza, 3 hours.
威廉会在那
William will be there.
达克说他会三小时后在尼尔森广场
Darhk says he's gonna release william
放了威廉
3 hours from now at nelson plaza.
不能相信达克说的话
There's no guarantee with Darhk.
这可能是个陷阱
This could be a trap.
现在我们有机会能除掉他获取力量的神像
And now we have a chance to take out his power idol thingy.
奥利  他失去了魔力
Ollie, without his magic,
就无法对任何人再做这种事了
he won't be able to do this to anybody ever again.
一切就都结束了
It--it will be game over.
萨曼莎
Samantha...
他是你的儿子
He's your son.
你来决定吧
It is your call.
他也是你的儿子  奥利弗
He's your son, too, Oliver.
把他救回来
Get him back
也把这个混蛋达克干掉
and take this son of a bitch Darhk out.
我看到十七个幽灵
I count 17 ghosts.
收到  黑金丝雀呢
Copy. Black Canary?
准备好了
Ready.
-斯巴达呢  -一切就绪
- Spartan? - I'm set.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
雌狐  该你上了
Vixen, you're up.
我猜你的保险不会给你报那个
I'm guessing your insurance won't pay for that.
真可爱  再见了
Cute. Bye-bye.
你死之后  我会保证
When you're dead, I'll make sure that totem
图腾会用在更合适的地方
gets put to better use.
我也正想这么跟你说
Took the words right out of my mouth.
好吧  发生了这种事
Well, that happened.
闪电妞  金丝雀  我没法瞄准
Speedy, Canary, I can't get a clear shot.
-你们在哪  -马上到
- Where are you? - On our way.
你们去找威廉
You find William.
我来解决达克
I'll take care of Darhk.
抱歉  我听不清你说什么
I'm sorry. I can't hear you with your throats
你嗓子太紧了
closing up like that.
别动
Steady.
我拿到图腾了  有什么作用吗
I've got the totem. Has it had any effect?
把它和达克分开毫无作用
Separating it from Darhk didn't do anything.
采取B计划
Go to plan "B."
B计划是什么
What's plan "B"?
求你不要伤害他们
Please don't hurt them.
威廉
William.
离开这里
Get out of here!
星城市警队
妈妈
Mom!
威廉
William!
医护人员检查过他  他毫发无损
Medics checked him out. He's in perfect health.
感谢苍天
Thank goodness.
你一定想他了吧
There's someone here that you must have missed.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我有点腻了闪电侠了
I'm kind of over the Flash.
我想要一个绿箭侠手办
I want a Green Arrow action figure.
也对  绿箭侠很厉害
Well, the Green Arrow is pretty amazing.
你们俩单独聊一会儿吧
I will let you guys get reacquainted.
嗨
Hey.
一切都好吗
Is everything ok?
医生检查威廉时
Detectives questioned William while the docs
警探询问了他一些问题
were checking him out.
不是达克把他带走的
Darhk didn't take him.
是一个少了一只手的人
It was a guy with a missing hand.
你这个混蛋
You son of a bitch!
我向你保证  奎恩先生
I assure you, Mr. Queen, I had all the faith
我完全相信你会活下来
in the world that you would survive.
那其他人呢
Well, what about everybody else?
我只关心你一个人的死活
You are my only concern.
因为你我们才进展到现在
We've gotten this far because of you.
我们把它完成吧
Let's finish it.
你也一起  维聂迪克托夫小姐
You, too, Miss Venediktov.
似乎你在身边时奎恩先生表现更好
Mr. Queen seems to behave at his best when you're around.
星城市警队
威廉会没事吧
Is William gonna be ok?
会的  他很坚强
Yeah. He's a tough one.
和他父亲一样
Just like his dad.
没有你我们做不到这些
Could not have done this without you.
谢谢
Thank you.
举手之劳
Anytime.
我说的话你仔细考虑了吗
Have you thought anymore about what I said?
我  我刚把他救回来
I--I just got him back.
我这么说吧  虽然被父母抛弃
Let me just say for all the frustrations
让我那么不开心
I have about my real parents giving me up,
但我还是很感激我的童年里
I am so grateful I was raised in a situation
被父母抛弃就是最大的烦恼
where that was my biggest issue in life.
我爸妈给我的最好礼物就是这种自由
Best things my parents ever gave me was that freedom.
当然还有这个图腾  才让我这么厉害
That and this totem, that makes me a total badass.
没有图腾你也很厉害
You don't need a totem for that.
这话是没错
You're damn right I don't.
好好照顾自己  奥利弗
Take care of yourself, Oliver.
一个电话我随时赶来
I'm just a phone call away.
我也是  玛丽  我也是
Me, too, Mari. Me, too.
听说你找到那孩子了
I heard you found the boy.
我真是太欣慰了
You can't believe how relieved I am.
-够了  -什么
- Cut the crap! - Excuse me?
我知道是你干的了
I know it was you.
你不怀好意带走了他
You took him out of spite!
是为了我们  你要相信那是为了我们
For us. You have to believe me I did it for us.
你完全  是故意害他陷入危险  你
You--you purposely-- you put him in danger. How--
我告诉你
You know what?
我不要再这样下去了
I'm not doing this anymore.
你来我家里说的那些大话
This song-and-dance where you come over to my apartment
那些一个又一个谎话
and you whisper your lies,
到此为止了
it is over!
西娅  我这么做是为了保护我们
Thea, I did it to protect us.
闭嘴  你怎么会以为
Shut up. How could you possibly think
我需要你保护
that there was an us to protect?
有时候  夜里我睡不着
You know, sometimes, I lay awake at night,
就在想罗伯特会怎么想我们的关系
and I wonder what Robert would think about our relationship.
他把我养大  爱着我
He raised me, he loved me,
我们相认的那刻我就失去了这一切
and I threw that all away the moment I became your daughter.
没错  那是你自己的选择
Yes. Yes, you did, and it was your choice.
真希望我没那么做
And I wish I never did.
你怎么敢这么跟我说话
Don't you dare speak to me like that.
要不是我你早都死了十几次了
You would be dead 10 times over if not for me.
是我教你如何战斗
I taught you how to fight,
教你自强
how to be strong.
把你从个被宠坏的弱女子变成了战士
I turned you from a delicate, spoiled brat into a warrior,
可我得到的只是你
and all I've ever gotten from you in return
恶毒的怨恨
is your venomous spite!
因为一切都怨你
For a very good reason!
你根本不知道你面对多么强大的敌人
You have no idea what you are up against.
你看不清大局
You are incapable of seeing the bigger picture,
我能
but I can,
我宁愿你活着恨我
and I would rather you hate me and be alive
也不要你爱着我死去
than love me and be dead.
你好  威廉
Hi, William.
希望你很好  很安全
I hope you're well, and I hope you're safe.
我有些事  想告诉你
There's something that I-- I want to tell you.
我之前就想告诉你
I wanted to tell you before,
但是...
but...
但是这样更好些
but this is better.
我是你的亲生父亲
I'm your father biologically, that is.
但是要说为你尽父亲的职责
As far as really being your father goes,
我还远未做到
I haven't earned that yet.
父亲应该每天都陪着孩子
A father should be there for his child every day
不论如何都要确保
no matter what to make sure
让孩子感觉到被爱着  有安全感
that they feel loved, that they feel safe,
孩子应该觉得父亲可以依赖
and a child should be able to rely on their father
可以从父亲那得到指导和安慰
and go to him for--for guidance and reassurance.
我没能为你做到这些
I have failed to do that for you...
现在  我告诉你为什么
and now I'm--I'm gonna tell you why.
我是绿箭侠
I'm the Green Arrow,
我的生活很危险  所以...
and my life is very dangerous, Which is why...
我们决定这些年里让你远离这种生活
we decided to keep you out of it for all these years.
你在星城遭遇的一切
What happened to you in Star City,
都是我的错
that was my fault,
我不能再让你遭遇这种事
and I can't allow anything like that to happen ever again,
所以我要求你妈妈
and that's why I've asked your mother to
带你远离这里
move you far away
不告诉任何人她要带你去哪里
and to not tell anyone where she's taking you,
包括我
including me.
也因为此  我要求她等你满18岁生日
It's also why I asked her to wait to show you this message
再给你看这个视频
until after your 18th birthday.
我希望你能拥有真正的童年
I wanted to give you a real childhood.
这是我想给你的礼物
I wanted to give you that gift.
再见  儿子
Good-bye, son.
肯定不会永远不见
I sure hope it's not forever.
你听到了多少
How much of that did you hear?
够多了
Enough.
奥利弗  我们需要谈谈
Oliver, we need to talk.
该谈的还不少
About a number of things, I suspect.
就从这个开始...
Let's start with...
我做不到
I can't do this.
你的儿子有危险  我只能
And your son was in danger, I have to table
把我的个人感情搁置一边
what I was feeling about everything,
但既然我有空去思考了
but now that I've had some space,
才发现我需要空间
I realize that I need space.
-费利西蒂  -我知道
- Felicity. - I know the postion
萨曼莎让你陷入的困境  我知道
Samantha put you in, I know
那是个两难的决定  但你是对的
it was a impossible decision, but you were right,
你该告诉我的
you should have told me.
忍受只是把一切憋在心里
Bear is just about inclusion.
你该做的是在事情变复杂时
It's about leaning on your partner
选择信任同伴
when things get complicated,
我觉得你不懂该怎么去做
I don't think that you know how to do that.
我...我在努力学
I'm... I'm trying.
现在  你要送威廉走  我很理解你
And now, you are sending William away, and I understand why.
你知道我理解的
You know that I do,
但你又一次没有告诉我
but once again, you have left me out of the decision.
费利西蒂
Felicity.
天哪
Oh my God.